baslerweb.com 2016-11-30

# Privacy Statement | Basler

Dear User,

We are pleased that you have visited the website of Basler AG and thank you for your interest in our company, our products, and our information.

The protection of your private sphere in the use of the Basler AG website is an important issue for us. For this reason we are in agreement with the applicable legal regulations for the protection of personal information and data security.

Data processing takes place in compliance with the following principles:

 **Use data**

If a web page of Basler AG is accessed, the following data is saved for a period of 7 days on the web server (managed by Kernpunkt GmbH, Köln):

Page, from which the file is requested

  * Name of the file
  * Date and time of the query
  * Transfered amount of data
  * Access status (file transfered, file not found, etc.)
  * Description of the type of web browser used
  * IP address of the requested computer

The information from the existing data information data previously described is exclusively evaluated for statistical purposes in order to gain an overview of the frequency of the access of individual segment offers. This evaluation helps us customize our web offers for your needs. This information is neither shared with third parties nor used for any other evaluation.  
 **  
Cookie Tracking**

Cookies are small text files that are stored by your browser when you visit some websites and use applications. You can define how websites use cookies by configuring the privacy settings in your browser (additional information on cookie settings can be found in the help function of your browser). If you deactivate cookies entirely, then websites and applications from Basler AG may under some circumstances not work properly.  
 **  
Google Analytics & Google Remarketing**

Google Analytics, the web analysis service from Google Inc. ("Google") and Google Remarketing, is used on the Basler AG website. Google Analytics and Google Remarketing use cookies to allow for an analysis of usage of the Basler websites.  
The information obtained by the cookies about the use of this website is generally transfered to a Google server in the USA and stored there.   
The IP anonymization is activated for the Basler AG website in order to guarantee the anonymous recording of IP addresses. Your IP address is then abbreviated by Google before being transfered within the member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. The complete IP address is abbreviated and transfered to a server in the USA only in exceptional cases. 

On behalf of Basler AG, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the Basler website, to compile reports about website activity, and to provide further information about the website use and the services connected to Internet use with respect to Basler AG. The information may be transmitted by Google to third parties where legally permitted or third parties are processing that data on behalf of Google.

On behalf of Basler AG, Google and third party providers will place Basler advertisements on the internet. The data collected by Google Analytics and Google Remarketing are used to place those ads. 

To prevent your data from being collected by Google Analytics during your visit to the Basler website, you may download and install the browser plug-in provided at the following link: ([http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)).

You can alternatively prevent Google Analytics from capturing data by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie is then set that prevents the future recording of your data when visiting this site.   
Click here to opt-out from Google Analytics

**Conversion Tracking**

Google Adwords Conversion Tracking is used on the Basler website. Conversion Tracking makes it possible to measure the entire number of users who have clicked on a Google advertisement of the Basler AG and been further directed to a page provided with a Conversion Tracking Tag. Basler AG does not retain information with which it is possible to personally identify users. 

A cookie is set on your computer by Google Adwords for Conversion Tracking when you have clicked on a Google advertisement on our website. These cookies are no longer valid after 30 days and are not capable of personally identifying the user. Your internet browser also includes settings to prevent cookies from being stored. 

**Pardot / Salesforce**

pardot, a marketing automation tool created by Pardot LLC, 950 East Paces Ferry Road, Suite 3300 Atlanta, GA 30326, USA is used on the Basler website.

pardot also uses the cookie tracking previously described to collect information about the use of the website. Your internet browser also includes settings to prevent cookies from being stored. Blocking cookies can however lead to limited functionality by the Basler website.

Further information about the handling of personal information and data from the European Union by Pardot LLC can be found here: http://www.pardot.com/company/legal/privacy-policy/  
 **  
Forms**

Personally relevant data which is entered into a form on the website of Basler AG is thereby used to establish contact with you and to provide you with the requested information.   
As an international company, all of our companies are thereby instructed to the greatest extent possible to have the same type of information. For this reason we transmit customer information to our subsidiaries and distributors in individual cases as necessary. In this regard then, there is no transmission of personal information to third parties.

 **Declaration of Consent Regarding Privacy**

By submitting a form, you agree that the information in respect of your usage of the Basler Web pages (e.g., pages visited and duration of visit to the respective pages, etc.) that is stored by pardot under a pseudonym may be aggregated with your personal data (form-based information) upon submitting this form. 

The aim of aggregating usage information with your personal data is to get to know you better as a potential customer and to make information that is of particular interest specifically to you available to you on our Web pages and via email. 

You may, at any time and with future effect, refuse – without providing substantiation – to allow the data aggregated in this manner to continue to be used by revoking your consent. To do so, please contact: [pardot-data-privacy@baslerweb.com](mailto:pardot-data-privacy@baslerweb.com)

**Basler Blog**

If you would like to leave a comment on the Basler Blog, you are required to provide your name and email address. The name, email address, and IP address of the commenter is visible to the administrator of the Basler Blogs. It is your decision as to whether or not you want to use the comment function. Basler retains the right to decide, for itself and at its own and free discretion, if a comment should be made public or not.

When a comment is made public in the Basler Blog, the entry and the name of the commenter is visible to the public. Therefore, before sending a comment, check that the comment only contains information that you would like to make publicly accessible.  
Please note that without any action on the part of Basler, search engines may index your comment and thereby be able to make it accessible world wide. Even after deleting or changing your original entry in the Basler Blog, your comment may still remain accessible on another location on the Internet.  
 ****

**Use of social plugins from Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+**

Social plugins are integrated on the website of Basler AG. These plugins enable the visitors of Basler websites to recommend the page contents via social media services such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+. 

The social plugins deployed on the Basler website follow the so-called 2-click principle in which users' data may only be transmitted to social media services after the agreement of the user.   
The social plugins on the Basler website are deactivated by default and have no contact with the servers from Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+. The plugins are only made active and establish a connection to the social media services after the user has activated the social plugin with a click and thereby declared agreement to communication with Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+. The user may then transmit the recommendation with a second click. The click on the button of the social plugin thus means that the user has given consent to transmit data to the respective operator of the social media service.  
Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+ do not provide specific information about which data is transmitted in the use of their social plugins. Basler AG therefore has no knowledge regarding the content and scope of the transmitted data or its use by Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Google+. Please refer to the further information about this in the data protection regulations of the social media services which are found here:   
[Facebook](https://en-gb.facebook.com/about/privacy/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en), [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy) and [Google+](http://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

By using the gear symbol within the social plugin bar on the Basler website you may permanently activate the social plugins. After permanently activating a social plugin, only one click is required to further recommend the page contents. Please note that if you do decide to permanently activate the social plugins, data is transmitted to the corresponding social media service immediately upon calling up the page.

**Your rights as the user**

According to § 34 and § 35 of the German Federal Data Protection Law, as the user you ("affected person") have the right to demand information at any time about which data has been saved by us and for what reason this has been saved. You may furthermore report incorrect data or have such data deleted which is invalidly stored or no longer required.  
 **  
Data protection requests**

Our external operational data protection officer is responsible for the compliance and monitoring of our data protection obligations. He is also available to you for further information at any time regarding data protection.

Dr. Uwe Schläger   
datenschutz nord GmbH
